Melle Dijkstra

Software Engineer Student

Application Developer • Computer Scientist

Wilgenlaan 12, Dokkum, 9103 SC The Netherlands (+31) 6 11 666 686 dev.melle@gmail.com

Profile

Experienced **Software Engineer** with 6 years of demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Currently in the 4th year of study with diverse **hard** and **soft** skills developed through various projects including **Team Leadership** and **Software Architecture**. As a **proactive**, analytical, and innovative individual I would be of excellent value in an internship position at companies that search for an ambitious and **highly motivated** young professional with previous **technical experience** and someone that is eager to **learn anything** that comes in its path.

Education

Software Engineering | Hanze University of Applied Sciences

BSc. Computer and Information Sciences, Bachelor of Science September 2016 - June 2020 (Anticipated), Groningen, The Netherlands

<u>Courses:</u> Website Development, Project Development, IT Service Management & Security, Data Analysis & Visualization, Algorithms & Data Structures, Network Infrastructures, Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning

Exchange Student | CEU San Pablo

Februari 2019 - June 2019, Madrid, Spain

<u>Courses:</u> Fundamentals of Marketing, Business Management and Organization II, Economic Theory II, Spanish

Application & Media Developer | MBO ROC Friese Poort

September 2014 - June 2016, Leeuwarden, The Netherlands

<u>Courses:</u> Design of Applications, Realization & Documenting Applications, Implementing Applications, Maintaining Applications

Experience

Application Developer | Bouw7

December 2015 - Present, Dokkum, The Netherlands

Bouw7 creates cloud-based software solutions for construction companies. Currently, I work on the creation of the web application, provide data analysis & visualization and create 3D solutions with Autodesk software.

Tasks include:

- Backend PHP development (with Symfony & Yii2 Framework)
- Frontend Development (HTML, Javascript & CSS)
- Server Management & Programming Environment (Linux systems & Docker)
- Autodesk Forge 3D Development
- Data Analysis & Visualization (Tableau, Google Analytics)

Intern Application Developer | Stroetenga Design

February 2016 - June 2016, Leeuwarden, The Netherlands

The internship consisted of developing a customer portal with Zend Framework 2. Also working in a team, planning and progression evaluation every week.

Task included:

- Team Management
- Planning and weekly progression evaluation

Engineering Intern | National Instructors College Abilonino

September 2018 - Januari 2019, Lira, Uganda

Challenging internship where one had to take into account that there is little to no internet accessibility. The main objective of the internship was offline accessibility and productivity improvement in administration.

Task included:

- Teaching programming skills to students
- Setting up two offline systems (Learning Management and Management Information System)
- Improving, regulating and monitoring the internet & intranet usage

Intern Media & Application Developer | <u>Kweekvijver Noord</u>

February 2015 - June 2015, Leeuwarden, The Netherlands

Internship at a creative company that develops websites, videos, documentaries, photos, animations, branding, applications and Virtual Reality solutions for various clients.

Tasks included:

- Creating creative solutions
- Contact with customers and getting to a solution
- ❖ Teamwork with people in different fields from Media & IT

· Farm Assistant | Common Ground Farm

July 2017 - August 2017, Saint Thomas, Ontario, Canada

— Skills

Technical Skills

- C#, Java, Python
- Web Development (PHP, Javascript, CSS, Symfony, Yii2)
- Databases
- Algorithms & Data Structures
- Android Development
- Operating Systems (Linux, Windows)
- Networking and Security Security
- Docker, Virtualization

Languages

- Dutch (Native)
- West Frisian (Native)
- English (Professional Proficiency)
- Spanish (Limited Working Proficiency)

Organizational skills

- Excellent communication skills
- Team Leadership and management skills
- Good presentation skills
- Documentation & Technical Writing

Honors & Awards

Finalist Skills Heroes

One of the finalists of the Skills Heroes 2016

The Skills Heroes is a professional competition for secondary vocational education in The Netherlands. Participants go through various qualification rounds and finally the national finals, participants compete in their field to become the best in the Netherlands.